# Lilin Xu

≥ lilinxu@zju.edu.cn

https://initxu.github.io/

 $\square$  +86 153-5615-9565

# **Biography**

I am an incoming PhD student at Columbia University in 2024 Fall. I obtained my M.E. degree from Zhejiang University in 2024, advised by Prof. Shibo He and Prof. Chaojie Gu. I am currently visiting The Chinese University of Hong Kong, working with Prof. Guoliang Xing and Prof. Zhenyu Yan.

My research interests are centered around **mobile sensing and AIoT** (AI + IoT), with a primary focus on **developing intelligent sensing systems** for practical applications, including human activity recognition, gesture interaction, etc.

## Education

Zhejiang University

Hangzhou, China

M.Eng. in Control Science and Engineering; GPA: 3.92/4.0

Sept. 2021 - Mar. 2024

Advisor: Prof. Shibo He & Prof. Chaojie Gu

Group of Networked Sensing and Control (NeSC), College of Control Science and Engineering

**Zhejiang University** 

Hangzhou, China

B.Eng. in Automation; **GPA:** 3.95/4.0, **Rank:** 5/120

Sept. 2017 – Jun. 2021

College of Control Science and Engineering

# Experience

#### The Chinese University of Hong Kong

Hong Kong

Visiting Student

Jan. 2024 – Present

Working with Prof. Guoliang Xing and Prof. Zhenyu Yan CUHK AIoT Lab, Department of Information Engineering

### Nanyang Technological University

Singapore

Visiting Student

Apr. 2023 - Oct. 2023

Working with Prof. Rui Tan

NTU IoT Research Group, School of Computer Science and Engineering

#### Selected Publications

[C1] GesturePrint: Enabling User Identification for mmWave-based Gesture Recognition Systems <u>Lilin Xu</u>, Keyi Wang, Chaojie Gu, Xiuzhen Guo, Shibo He, Jiming Chen ICDCS 2024 (Acceptance ratio: 121/552=21.9%)

• GesturePrint is the first one-stop solution for mmWave-based gesture recognition with user identification, which can extract effective features from gesture point clouds by the proposed preprocessing pipeline and GesIDNet; we build a new gesture dataset including 9,332 samples from 17 participants performing 15 ASL gestures in two different environments.

[C2] MESEN: Exploit Multimodal Data to Design Unimodal Human Activity Recognition with Few Labels

Lilin Xu, Chaojie Gu, Rui Tan, Shibo He, Jiming Chen

**SenSys 2023** (Acceptance ratio: 34/179=**19**%)

• MESEN is the first multimodal-empowered unimodal sensing framework utilizing the increasing availability of multimodal data to universally enhance unimodal human activity recognition, which exploits the correlations and relationships within unlabeled multimodal data for effective unimodal feature extraction.

[C3] Generalized Global Ranking-Aware Neural Architecture Ranker for Efficient Image Classifier Search Bicheng Guo, Tao Chen, Shibo He, Haoyu Liu, <u>Lilin Xu</u>, Peng Ye, Jiming Chen

#### ACM Multimedia 2022

• NAR is the first global architecture performance ranker with a generalizable ranking ability.

 $[J1] \ Latency-aware \ Neural \ Architecture \ Performance \ Predictor \ with \ Query-to-Tier \ Technique \ Bicheng \ Guo, \ \underline{Lilin \ Xu}, \ Tao \ Chen, \ Peng \ Ye, \ Shibo \ He, \ Haoyu \ Liu, \ Jiming \ Chen$ 

# IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology

• NARQ2T is the first end-to-end architecture performance (accuracy & latency) predictor to match neural architectures to various quality tiers and guide the architecture sampling in the search phrase.

#### Selected Awards and Honors

Columbia University Presidential Fellowship	2024
Zhejiang University Sun Youxian Scholarship (Top 1%)	2024
Zhejiang University Outstanding Graduate Student	2024
SenSys'23 SIG Student Travel Grant	2023
Zhejiang University Wen Chixiang Scholarship	2023
Zhejiang University Award of Honor for Graduate Student	2022 & 2023
AI Studio 2022 CVPR Track2: Performance Estimation Track, Top 10 Award (8/190) 2022	
College Academic Excellence First-prize Scholarship	2022 & 2023
Zhejiang University First-prize Scholarship (Top 3%)	2019
Zhejiang University Outstanding Student Honor	2019
Zhejiang University Second-prize Scholarship	2018 & 2020

## Professional Service

- Web Chair of ACM SenSys 2024
- Student Volunteer of IPSN 2024

# Technical Skills

**Programming Skills** Python, C++, Java, MATLAB, JavaScript

Tools & Frameworks PyTorch, TensorFlow